{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
<<<<<<< HEAD
<<<<<<< HEAD
      "question": "The sand replacement method can also be called as _________ .",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Sand cone method",
        "b": "Sand bar method",
        "c": "Sand dry method",
        "d": "Sand jar method"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "In the sand replacement method a hole is excavated in the soil and it is filled with free flowing sand from the conical shape of the container. Hence the sand replacement  method is also called the sand cone method.",
        "b": "Sandbars are the deposition of sand along the shore of a river. This is not the method  for sand replacement.",
        "c": "The sand is mined, washed, screened and stored in piles. The process of drying sand to a required moisture content is the sand dry method. This is not the method for sand replacement.",
        "d": "This is the method used to estimate the texture of soil by making the soil particle settle in a jar containing water."
=======
      "question": "The measurement of compaction can be performed in terms of ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Permeability",
        "b": "Compressibility",
        "c": "Specific gravity",
        "d": "Dry density"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
>>>>>>> cf583c7ef42d0fa41b293d17023371b684a03cf6
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
<<<<<<< HEAD
      "question": "The codebook referred for conducting Sand Replacement method is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "IS : 2720 part 29 1974",
        "b": "IS : 2720 part 28 1974",
        "c": "IS : 2720 part 27 1975",
        "d": "IS : 2720 part 26 1975"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "This standard is used for determination of in-place density by core cutter method.",
        "b": "Right answer. This standard is used for determination of dry density of soil, in-place, by sand replacement  method.",
        "c": "This standard is used for determination of total soluble Sulphates in soil.",
        "d": "This standard is used for determination of pH value."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The full form of FDD is ________________________.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Full Dry Density",
        "b": "Full Dug Density",
        "c": "Field Dug Density",
        "d": "Field Dry Density"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "The full form of FDD is Field Dry Density, where F stands for Field not Full.",
        "b": "The full form of FDD is Field Dry Density, it is not Full Dug Density.",
        "c": "In full form of FDD, D stands for Dry not Dug.",
        "d": "The form of FDD is Field Dry Density."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "Relative compaction is defined as the ratio of _______________________________.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Field dry density and lab dry density.",
        "b": "Partial dry density and total dry density.",
        "c": "Lab dry density and field dry density.",
        "d": "Total dry density and partial dry density."
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Relative compaction is the ratio of field dry density to lab dry density.",
        "b": "It is the ratio of dry density of field and lab. It is not partial dry density and total dry density.",
        "c": "It is the ratio between field and lab dry density. It is not the ratio of lab dry density and field dry density.",
        "d": "Relative compaction is not the ratio of total dry density  and partial dry density."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "The qualities of sand used in the sand replacement method are _______.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Dry",
        "b": "Clean ",
        "c": "uniform",
        "d": "All the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "The sand used for the sand replacement method should be dry so that it does not stick to each other and it flows easily.",
        "b": "The sand used for the sand replacement method should be clean. It should not contain other materials like debris, twigs etc.",
        "c": "The texture of sand should be uniform so that it passes easily through the opening provided.",
        "d": "The quality of sand used for sand replacement should be dry, clean, and uniform.  Hence all the above provided options are correct."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "advanced"
=======
      "question": "The aim of compaction is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Decreasing dry density ",
        "b": "Increasing porosity",
        "c": "Decreasing void ratio",
        "d": "Decreasing shear strength"
      },
      "explanations": {
=======
      "question": "The measurement of compaction can be performed in terms of ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Permeability",
        "b": "Compressibility",
        "c": "Specific gravity",
        "d": "Dry density"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The aim of compaction is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Decreasing dry density ",
        "b": "Increasing porosity",
        "c": "Decreasing void ratio",
        "d": "Decreasing shear strength"
      },
      "explanations": {
>>>>>>> cf583c7ef42d0fa41b293d17023371b684a03cf6
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the correct statement? Vibratory rollers are suitable for compacting _____________.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Organic soil",
        "b": "Clays",
        "c": "Sand and gravels",
        "d": "Clay silts"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "As the Compaction increases, the porosity decreases.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "False",
        "b": "True"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following does not produce compaction?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Vibration",
        "b": "Tamping",
        "c": "Rolling",
        "d": "Adding excess water"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
<<<<<<< HEAD
>>>>>>> cf583c7ef42d0fa41b293d17023371b684a03cf6
=======
>>>>>>> cf583c7ef42d0fa41b293d17023371b684a03cf6
    }
  ]
}
